A Guide to the Papers of John Dos Passos 1865-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John Dos Passos 1865-1998
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
5950
The collection consists of ca. 50,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection is a consolidation of gift and other acquisitions received in the Special Collections Department of the University of Virginia over the period 1958-1999 from: John Dos Passos, his wife Elizabeth Holdridge Dos Passos, his daughter Lucy Dos Passos Coggin and from a number of friends and associates that include: Thomas Pym Cope, Mrs. Lloyd (Marion) Lowndes, Mrs. Harold Weston, Connie and William White, Edmund Berkeley, Jr., Charles W. Bernardin, Jack Diggens, Kenneth C. Duckett, Philip L. Gerber, Townsend Ludington and Ray Lewis White.
Scope and Content
The Dos Passos papers at the University of Virginia present a vivid chronicle of the author's activities, thoughts and literary skills as he analyzed, reported on and criticized the turbulent events of the 20th century. Dos Passos, identifying with the leftist radical sympathies of the post-World War I period, experimented in expressing these sentiments with innovative writing techniques in some of his most important and successful works: One Man's Initiation--1917 (1920), Three Soldiers (1921), Manhattan Transfer (1925) and the trilogy, USA (The 42nd Parallel, 1930; Nineteen Nineteen, 1932; The Big Money, 1936).
The collection highlights the Dos Passos chronicle principally through a large body of manuscripts, letters and other personal and family related papers that have been assembled at the University of Virginia over the past 40 years from a series of gifts from Dos Passos and later, from his widow Elizabeth, and his daughter Lucy Dos Passos Coggin. Also included is a small quantity of gift acquisitions from several close friends and associates.
The major portion of the papers is comprised of manuscript material (published and unpublished) of most of his novels, plays, poems, articles, speeches, lectures, readings and his reportage on history, politics, society and travel. Included are corrected and uncorrected typescripts, galley and page proofs, notes, outlines, related research material and an extensive assemblage of publisher and literary agent correspondence. Of particular interest are his diaries and notebooks filled with recorded observations, thoughts, verse and sketches that may have served as the basis for some of the character development and themes found in his published writings and in his works of art.
Another large part of the collection contains letters written to him over his lifetime from close friends, literary associates and random correspondents which comprise a narrative, of sorts, of the conflicting political, social and cultural ideas that he and others of his generation grappled with in the period between the two World Wars. Letters from his close friends and literary associates include, among others, those from E.E. Cummings, Ernest Hemingway, John Howard Lawson, Archibald MacLeish, Walter Rumsey Marvin, Gerald Murphy, Dudley Poore and Edmund Wilson.
The balance of the collection consists of Dos Passos family papers, along with a small assortment of other miscellaneous material. The family papers contain correspondence Dos Passos exchanged with his parents, his wife Katharine and other collateral relatives. Included among Dos Passos' personal papers are financial, legal, and household data; mementos of his awards and honors; originals and copies of his drawings and paintings; articles and newsclips about his life and his writings; and a collection of photographs of his childhood years, portraits and snapshots of him as a young adult and family photographs of the period 1950 through 1960. In later years, Dos Passos turned from the radicalism of his youth. He settled in the family home in Westmoreland County in northern Virginia with his wife Elizabeth Holdridge Dos Passos and their daughter Lucy where he continued to pursue, with his characteristic vigor, the engagement of his new found political and social ideas into his writings, lectures and speeches.
He died on September 28, 1970 and remains as one of the pre-eminent writers of the 20th century.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in four series: I--Correspondence, II--Writings, III--Personal, IV--Miscellaneous.
Series I: Correspondence General correspondence with Dos Passos: (Boxes 1-11) Correspondence with attached and related material exchanged between John Dos Passos and lifelong friends and associates, literary colleagues, critics, editors, organizations and the general public. Material is organized alphabetically by the name of the correspondent and is listed separately for both the items sent to Dos Passos and those prepared by him. Included among others, are letters exchanged with E.E. Cummings, Ernest Hemingway, Robert Hillyer, John Howard Lawson, Archibald MacLeish, Walter Rumsey Marvin, Dudley Poore and Edmund Wilson. General correspondence between others: (Box 11) A small amount of third party correspondence not directly involved with Dos Passos. Listed alphabetically by the name of the recipient. Family correspondence with Dos Passos: (Boxes 12-15) The largest portion is of the correspondence exchange between Dos Passos and his parents (1890-1917) and the letters exchanged with his first wife, Katharine Smith Dos Passos (1928-1946). The remaining smaller portion is with other collateral relatives. Family correspondence between others: (Boxes 16-17) Mostly letters to his mother, Lucy S. Madison from his father, John Randolph Dos Passos before and after their marriage (1892-1913) and letters by his father to a cousin, Ida Pifer (1900-1912). Publisher-related correspondence with Dos Passos: (Boxes18-21) Correspondence between Dos Passos and his domestic and foreign literary agents relating to the publication and marketing of his writings. Also included are permission requests from authors and editors to use his work, communications and contracts concerning his lecture activities and, from the Brandt and Brandt literary agency, their "Dos Passos office file" with almost 2500 items of their worldwide correspondence dealings regarding Dos Passos' writings.
Series II: Writings Published works on society, politics, history and travel: (Boxes 22-109) Manuscripts, galleys, notes, outlines, typed drafts, research material, correspondence and reviews relating to Dos Passos' published writings. Arranged alphabetically by the title of the work. Contributions to books, periodicals and newspapers: (Boxes 110-112) Manuscripts, notes, outlines, typed drafts, research material and print copies of Dos Passos' prose and verse contributions. Arranged alphabetically by the title of the work and listing the name and date of the publication. Dos Passos' prose and verse of undetermined publication: (Boxes 113-117) Manuscripts and typescripts that appear to be in his hand and that contain his notations but that have not been determined to have been published. Some appear to be manuscript portions that may relate to earlier versions of a published work. Arranged alphabetically by the title of the work or the opening line. Prose and verse of undetermined authorship and publication: (Box 117) Manuscripts not in Dos Passos' hand and typescripts that do not bear any of his notations. Arranged alphabetically by the title of the work or the opening line. Speech material: (Boxes 117-118) Notes, outlines, background and presentation drafts for specific speech events, readings from his published books and for other unidentified talks. Research and background: (Boxes 118-121) Background print material, notebooks, outlines and miscellaneous loose drafts relating to various research topics. Emphasis on Jefferson and on American and English history.
Series III: Personal Artwork by Dos Passos: (Box 122) His pencil sketches, black and white photographs and color reproductions of his watercolor art, and catalogues of his artwork showings. Artwork collected by Dos Passos: (Box 122) Drawings, sketches and watercolors from a variety of artists collected over the years by Dos Passos. Included also are classical and contemporary musical recordings and sheet music. Awards: (Box 122-125) Mostly certificates and accompanying correspondence and mementos of the honorary tributes bestowed upon Dos Passos for his writings, his educational activities, his influence in the political arena and for his service (non-combative) in the two World Wars. Also included is a video produced in 1996 that commemorates his 100th Anniversary. Diaries and note books: (Box 125-126) Literary and travel books with prose, verse, sketches, observations and commentary compiled by Dos Passos in the years 1911-1927 during his sojourns in Europe and the Middle East. Memorabilia: (Boxes 127-129) An assortment of personal papers, certificates, newsclips, passports, postcards, school records, mementos of World Wars I and II and other keepsakes collected and saved by Dos Passos during his lifetime. Arranged and listed alphabetically by the descriptive name of each item. Personal data: (Boxes 129-130) A small collection of personal papers and documents organized and arranged chronologically by date in financial, legal, medical and household property categories. Photographs: (Boxes 130-133) Photographs of Dos Passos, his family, his close friends and associates and of his activities from his childhood to his later years. Organized alphabetically by subject, location, event or name of person. Writings and reviews about Dos Passos: (Boxes 133-139) Published and unpublished articles, interviews, newsclips and other writings about the life and work of Dos Passos. Arranged and listed alphabetically by the title of the writing.
Series IV: Miscellaneous Papers pertaining to other family members: (Boxes 139-142) Of particular interest are the writings of his father John Randolph Dos Passos, a prominent lawyer active in the national party politics of the late 19th and early 20th centuries and author of articles and essays on the Supreme Court, the recognition of Cuba, woman suffrage and the war in Europe. His papers also include a number of autograph signed letters from some of the notable personalities of the period: William Borah, William Jennings Bryan, Josephus Daniels, Jay Gould, Benjamin Harrison, Charles Evans Hughes, Henry Cabot Lodge and Woodrow Wilson. The papers of Dos Passos' first wife, Katharine contain a number of her short story manuscripts and correspondence that includes autograph signed letters and a poem from Ernest and Pauline Hemingway. The other family papers are primarily correspondence, writings and memorabilia organized under the name of the person to whom the material pertains. Papers pertaining to friends and associates: (Box 143) A small quantity of correspondence, writings and memorabilia of his close friends, Arthur McComb, Wright McCormick and Dudley Poore that relate to the period of the early 20th century. The papers of Charles W. Bernardin, who interacted extensively with Dos Passos while attempting to write and publish a biography about him, contain a scholarly dissertation and unpublished manuscripts on Dos Passos and his writings. Included also are Dos Passos family photographs and a large volume of correspondence that was exchanged with Dos Passos during 1942-1966. The Bernardin material has been relocated to the appropriate sections of the collection (See boxes 1, 2, 94, 130-133, 137-139). The personal papers relating solely to Bernardin are in box 143. Other writings and print matter: (Boxes 143-144) Miscellaneous manuscripts by named and anonymous authors and other print matter that may have been of interest to Dos Passos as memorabilia or as background.
Contents List
  Series I
- Correspondence
  - General correspondence with Dos Passos (Box 1-11)
    Correspondence with attached and related material exchanged between John Dos Passos and lifelong friends and associates, literary colleagues, critics, editors, organizations and the general public. Material is organized alphabetically by the name of the correspondent and is listed separately for both the items sent to Dos Passos and those prepared by him. Included among others, are letters exchanged with E.E. Cummings, Ernest Hemingway, Robert Hillyer, John Howard Lawson, Archibald MacLeish, Walter Rumsey Marvin, Dudley Poore and Edmund Wilson.
    - Ackerman, Adolph J. 1966 (Box 1)
    - Adjutant, Sorbonne Detachment May 20, 1919 (Box 1)
      re: leave application (by John Dos Passos)
    - Agnew, Spiro T. 1970 (Box 1)
    - Aita, Antonio 1962, 2 items (Box 1)
    - Albert, Charles 1919 (Box 1)
    - Alford, S. 1920 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Frederica L. 1943 (Box 1)
    - Amanda 1925 (Box 1)
    - Amélia, Maria n.d. (Box 1)
    - American Civil Liberties Union 1952 (Box 1)
      re: his resignation (by John Dos Passos)
    - Arredordo, Rafael 1966 (Box 1)
    - Austin, Oliver and Elizabeth 1964-1967, 3 items (Box 1)
    - Arturo [de Tenoya?] [1918 APril 11?] (Box 1)
    - Baker, Carlos 1966, n.d., 7 items (Box 1)
    - Baltimore Sun, Editor 1962 (Box 1)
      re: Peabody Library (by John Dos Passos)
    - Banus, Mario Garcia 1947 (Box 1)
    - Barea, Arturo and Alsa 1939, 2 items (Box 1)
    - Barnicoat and Sons 1947 (Box 1)
      re: wife's burial stone
    - Barquet, Nicholas 1956 (Box 1)
    - Barry, Griffin 1938 (Box 1)
    - Barry, Griffin 1919, 2 items (Box 1)
      by John Dos Passos
    - Basshe, Em Jo n.d. (Box 1)
    - Baudisch, Paul (Box 1)
    - Bautile, G.H. [1918?] January 14 (Box 1)
    - Beal, Fred Erwin 1941 (Box 1)
    - Becker, Ray 1935 (Box 1)
    - Belew, William W. 1941 (Box 1)
    - Bernardin, Charles W. 1942-1996, n.d., 140 items Box 1: (1-7 of 10 folders) Box 2: (8-10 of 10 folders) (Box 1-2)
    - Biddle, James 1970 (Box 2)
    - Biensen, Tyler n.d. (Box 2)
    - Bienstock, N.S. 1944 (Box 2)
    - Bill (University of Missouri) 1946 (Box 2)
    - Billingsley, Kirby 1943 (Box 2)
    - Bird, William 1956 (Folder 2)
    - Bishop, John Peale 1942 (Box 2)
    - Blanc, Carmen Heath 1944-1945, 5 items (Box 2)
      re: Francesca Dos Passos
    - Bland, Gladwin, (Gladdie) 1932 (Box 2)
    - Bland, Karl W. (Marx) 1932-1938, 2 items (Box 2)
    - Bliss, Edward Gering 1962, by John Dos Passos (Box 2)
    - Blodgett, Glen W. 1924 (Box 1)
    - Bob and Betsy 1947, 2 items (Box 2)
    - Bowers, Claude 1939 (Box 2)
    - Boyd, Julian and Adair, Douglass 1955, n.d., 3 items (Box 2)
      Contains undated typescript notes on John Dos Passos's book, The Head and Heart of Thomas Jefferson (1954)
    - Brockunier, Samuel Hugh 1939-1940, 3 items (Box 2)
    - Brod and McGuire[?] n.d. (Box 2)
    - Bromfield, Ellen 1967-1970, 5 items (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Van Wyck 1962 (Box 2)
    - Brooks, Wendell S. 1940 (Box 2)
    - Brown, Mary E. n.d. (Box 2)
    - Brown, Rollo Walter 1925 (Box 2)
    - Buckley, William F. 1966-1970, 3 items (Box 2)
    - Bush, Martin H. 1964 (Box 2)
    - Byrd, Harry F., Jr. 1965-1970, 2 items (Box 2)
    - Byrnes, Oscar 1938, n.d., 2 items (Box 2)
    - Cabell, Mrs. Hartwell 1965, by John Dos Passos (Box 2)
    - Cadwalader, Thomas F. 1969 (Box 2)
    - Calhoun, Filmore n.d., 2 items (Box 2)
    - Cameron, Brodnax and/or Julia 1956-1970, n.d., 4 items (Box 2)
    - Cantwell, Robert 1936-1942, n.d., 4 items (Box 2)
    - Cantwell, Robert 1934-1967, n.d., 10 items by John Dos Passos (see also box 139) (Box 2)
    - Cardozo, Mário 1967 (Box 2)
    - Carlsmith, Carl S. 1945 (Box 2)
    - Carter, E. Gayle 1940 (Box 2)
    - Cendrars, Blaise 1929-1937, 12 items (Box 2)
    - Centuty Association 1970 (Box 2)
      re: William F. Buckley (by John Dos Passos)
    - Chambers, Canby 1947, n.d., 2 items (Box 2)
    - Charles n.d. (Box 2)
    - Charlie 1941 (Box 2)
    - Chermayett, Lenge n.d. (Box 2)
    - Cintra, Luis F. Lindley 1962 (Box 2)
    - Claffey, John T. 1922 (Box 2)
    - Clark, David Lee 1944 (Box 2)
      re: The Big Money controversy at University of Texas
    - Clark, Ernest 1936 (Box 2)
    - Clements, Robert J. 1944 (Box 2)
      re: Mediæval Academy of America
    - Colymes[?], C. n.d. (Box 2)
    - Conant, Kenneth n.d., 2 items (Box 2)
    - Cope, Thomas Pym 1918-1931, n.d., 29 items (Box 2)
    - Cope, Thomas Pym 1919-1922, 10 items (Box 2)
    - Cope, Mrs. Walter 1918, 2 items by John Dos Passos (Box 2)
    - Cordell, Roy L. M. 1922 (Box 2)
    - Coyle, Albert F. 1929 (Box 3)
    - Cummings, E.E. [Edward Estlin] and Marion 1919-1963, n.d., 13 items (Box 148)
    - Cummings, E.E. [Edward Estlin] and Ann 1917-1933, n.d., 18 items by John Dos Passos (Box 3)
    - Cupit, A., 1943 (Box 3)
    - Currence, John D., M.D. 1935 (Box 3)
    - Curtis, Richard Cary 1940 (Box 3)
    - Da Costa, Eliseu 1963-1968, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Daubney, Robert H. 1936 (Box 3)
    - Day, Peg n.d. (Box 3)
    - De Beer, Dora H. 1913-1919, n.d., 5 items (Box 3)
    - De Castro ye Polly Boyden, Baldorioty n.d. (Box 3)
    - De Carvalho, Pedro Xisto 1959 (Box 3)
    - De Ferrandin, Florencia 1940, 2 items (Box 3)
      with ANS, S. Panjay Seizlauseco[?]
    - De la Serna, Victor 1964 (Box 3)
    - Delgado, Rafael 1943 (Box 3)
    - den Boer, Willem n.d. (Box 3)
    - De S., Los E. 1919-1922, n.d., 3 items (Box 3)
    - De Silver, Margaret 1937-1940, n.d., 6 items (Box 3)
    - De Vasconcellos, Dora Alencar n.d. (Box 3)
    - Dewey, John 1937-1938, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Diggens, Jack 1966, 2 items (Box 3)
      re: Carlo Tresca (by John Dos Passos)
    - Donovan, Mary 1939 (Box 3)
    - Dore, John 1967 (Box 3)
    - Dreiser, Theodore 1936 (Box 148)
    - Drury, Allen 1969 (Box 3)
    - Dudley, Caroline 1925-1956, n.d., 20 items (Box 3)
    - Dupee, Fred 1965-1966, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Durand, Mrs. F. A. 1947 (Box 3)
    - Dwight, H. G. 1941 (Box 3)
    - Eastman, Max 1947-1961, 3 items (Box 3)
    - Eastman, Max 1944 (Box 3)
    - Edwards, Ted 1932 (Box 3)
    - Ehrhard, Lyn n.d. (Box 3)
    - Eichner, Alfred S. 1964 (Box 3)
    - Embree, Edwin R. 1936-1940, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Escuder, América 1945 (Box 3)
    - Esther 1943-1946, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Evelyn 1940 (Box 3)
    - Fallaci, Oriana 1967 (Box 3)
    - Faria, José Gomes 1966 (Box 3)
    - Farnsworth, Henka 1947-1967, n.d., 27 items (Box 3)
    - Farrell, James T. 1941-1958, 15 items (Box 3)
    - Farwell, F. Evans 1970 (Box 3)
    - Fell, Polly (Mrs. Richard Fell) 1962 (Box 3)
    - Ferreira, Ramón 1966-1968, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Fernsworth, Lawrence A. 1938 (Box 3)
    - Field, George 1966 (Box 3)
      re: Mihajlo Mihajlov
    - Finnerty, John F. 1945, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott 1934-1936, 2 items (Box 148)
    - Fitzgerald, William C. 1967 (Box 3)
    - Fitzgerald, Zelda n.d. (Box 148)
    - Forss[?], Harry 1934 (Box 3)
      with poems about the IWW
    - Francis n.d. (Box 3)
    - Frank, Waldo 1916-1929, 3 items (Box 3)
    - Fred 1921-1922, 3 items (Box 3)
    - French, Hazel 1918 (Box 3)
    - Freyre, Gilberto 1961 (Box 3)
    - Friede, Juan[?] n.d. (Box 3)
    - Fritz 1957 (Box 3)
    - Funaroff, S. 1933 (Box 3)
    - Fund for Adult Education 1955 (Box 3)
    - Fund for Intellectual Freedom 1961 (Box 3)
    - Galantière, Lewis n.d., 2 items (Box 3)
    - Galdamez, Joanna 1965, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Gannett, Lewis 1960-1965, n.d., 9 items (Box 3)
    - Gantt, Andrew H. II (Andy) 1957-1966, 3 items (Box 3)
    - Gantt, William Horsley 1941-1970, n.d., 17 items (Box 3)
    - Gantt, William Horsley 1954, 4 items (Box 3)
    - Gantt, Mrs. William Horsley (Dickie) 1964 (Box 3)
    - Gantt, Col. Henry P. 1933, 1969, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Garcia, J. Cueva 1945, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Garcitoral, Alicio 1964-1967, 2 items (Box 3)
    - Garst, Roswell (Bob) 1957 (Box 3)
    - Gattorno, Antonio 1936-1946, n.d., 4 items (Box 3)
    - Gattorno, Isabel 1945 (Box 3)
    - Gaylor, Adelaide Lawson 1921-1970, 13 items (Box 3)
    - Gee, Mrs. K. A. (Auntie Kate) 1912-1932, n.d., 22 items (Box 4)
    - George and Eva 1940, n.d., 2 items (Box 4)
    - Georges 1919 (Box 4)
    - Gibson, William 1940 (Box 4)
    - Gilbert, Edward M. 1963-1964, 2 items (Box 4)
    - Gillam, Stanley 1966 (Box 4)
    - Giner, Jose (Pepe) 1918-1950, n.d., 12 items (Box 4)
    - Giordano, Francesco 1918 (Box 4)
    - Given, Phyllis and Eben 1948-1967, n.d., 23 items (Box 4)
    - Glaspell, Susan and Bill 1931-1934, n.d., 6 items (Box 4)
    - Goodwin, Murray 1941 (Box 4)
    - Gomez, Maximo Pacheco 1969 (Box 4)
    - Gorrin, Paul 1965 (Box 4)
    - Graham, Sheila n.d., 2 items (Box 4)
    - Grier, William T. 1957 (Box 4)
    - Griffith, E. C. 1944 (Box 4)
    - Groz, George 1936 (Box 4)
    - Grupp, George W. 1947 (Box 4)
    - "Guggles" [William B. Smith, Jr.] 1925 (Box 4)
    - Gummen, Tommy 1904 (Box 4)
    - Hackett, Chauncey and Bubs 1933-1952, n.d., 34 items (Box 4)
    - Hackett, Hennen (Winks) and Wendy Everett 1966-1967, n.d., 8 items (Box 4)
    - Hale 1941 (Box 4)
    - Hall, Rody 1934 (Box 4)
    - Hall, T. Edward 1945 (Box 4)
    - Hamlin, Talbot 1944 (Box 4)
    - Hapgood, Hutch n.d. (Box 4)
    - Harding, T. Swann 1940 (Box 4)
    - Hardwick, C. Vincent 1943 (Box 4)
    - Harris, Mary E. (his mother's nurse) 1912-1915, n.d., 11 items (Box 4)
    - Harris, Mrs. Mary E. 1912, n.d., 4 items (Box 4)
    - Hart, Harry n.d. (Box 4)
    - Haynes, James L. 1962 (Box 4)
    - Hazell, Lois n.d. (Box 4)
    - Hellendale, Jill Hibben n.d., 4 items (Box 4)
      with Sheila Hibben ALS
    - Hemingway, Ernest 1925-1951, n.d., 32 items, in 28 folders (Box 148)
    - Hemingway, Ernest 1925-1961, n.d., 93 items, in 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Hemingway, Hadley 1947 (Box 148)
    - Hemingway, Mary 1965, 2 items (Box 4)
      with Valerie Danby-Smith TLS
    - Hemingway, Pauline 1947-1948, n.d., 5 items (Box 4)
      with KSDP ALSs
    - Henderson, John n.d. (Box 5)
    - Henry and Murray 1919 (Box 5)
    - Heuer, Mr. n.d. (Box 5)
    - Hibben, Paxton 1925 (Box 5)
    - Hibben, Sheila 1940-1942, n.d., 3 items (Box 5)
    - Hill, Ginny Carpenter 1947 (Box 5)
    - Hillyer, Robert Silliman 1918-1961, n.d., 24 items (Box 5)
    - Hillyer, Robert Silliman 1921 (Box 5)
    - Hinton, Harry n.d. (Box 5)
    - Hinton, Henrietta 1910 (Box 5)
    - Hook, Sidney 1934, 2 items (Box 5)
    - Hunt, Mr. 1965 (Box 5)
    - Hurralde, Maximo 1936 (Box 5)
    - Ivens, Joris 1936, 2 items (Box 5)
      re: "Dream Factory"
    - Jack (Marine Experimental Station) 1950, n.d., 2 items (Box 5)
    - Janie, Gordon 1967, n.d., 2 items (Box 5)
    - Jelliffe, Belinda n.d. (Box 5)
    - Jenkins, Mrs. Burris Jr. 1947 (Box 5)
    - John 1939 (Box 5)
    - John and Hattie 1955-1967, 2 items (Box 5)
    - Jonas, Klaus 1945 (Box 5)
    - Jones, Howard Mumford 1947 (Box 5)
    - Josephson, Matthew 1932 (Box 5)
      re: Nineteen Nineteen
    - Judson, Mrs. F. A. (Marguerite M.) 1966 (Box 5)
    - Julie 1964 (Box 5)
    - Kaeselau, Chris ca. early 1940s (Box 5)
    - Kaeselau, Jean 1945-1946 (Box 5)
    - Kay, Josephine 1943 (Box 5)
    - Keller, Dr. 1968 (Box 5)
    - Kennedy, John F. 1961 (Box 148)
    - Klabin, Horacio 1966 (Box 5)
    - Koltzov n.d. (Box 5)
    - Kraschutzki, H. 1945-1946, 2 items (Box 5)
    - Kubie, Dr. Lawrence S. 1970 (Box 5)
    - Lacerda, Carlos 1968-1969, 3 items (Box 5)
    - La Follette, Fola 1960 (Box 5)
    - Lafourcade, Enrique y Murta 1970 (Box 5)
    - Lambrecht, Klaus 1940, n.d., 2 items (Box 5)
    - Lancaster, H. C. 1946, 2 items (Box 5)
    - Lawson, John Howard (Jack) 1921-1967, n.d., 34 items (Box 5)
    - Lawson, Kate Drain 1919, 1956, n.d., 10 items (Box 5)
      with poem and photo
    - Lazenby, Mary E. 1963 (Box 5)
      re: Ellen Wilson Holmes
    - Lecomte, T. 1919 (Box 5)
    - Leeds, William B. 1964-1966, 5 items (Box 5)